□ 952-297-6289 | Imsure 95@gmail.com | Mimsure.github.io | Imsure | Imshuo-yang-12ab7047

Summary_

Looking for a job as a Software Engineer. 8 years of programming experience with C/C++, Python and Java, specializing in system programming and backend/infrastructure. Proficient in Relational Database Management Systems, especially MySQL. Experienced with Big Data technology such as Hadoop and Hive. Good exposure to NoSQL databases such as MongoDB and HBase. Enjoys working with Emacs, Linux and OSX for development. Eager to learn new technologies and tools to grow professionally.

Education

University of Arizona

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, GPA: 3.18

University of St. Thomas

M.S. IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING, GPA: 3.8

Harbin Institute of Technology

B.E. IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

Tucson, Arizona USA

Aug. 2014 - May. 2017

St. Paul, Minnesota USA

Aug. 2011 - May. 2014

Harbin, Heilongjiang China

Aug. 2004 - May. 2008

Academic Experience

University of Arizona USA Tucson, Arizona USA

RESEARCH ASSISTANT WITH DR. RICHARD SNODGRASS ON ANTARES PROJECT

Aug. 2016 - Mar. 2017

- Main developer of ANTARES (The Arizona-NOAO Temporal Analysis and Response to Events System) project.
- Deployed ANTARES system to the dedicated CentOS cluster using MySQL Cluster as Database backend.
- Analyzed and improved the performance of ANTARES data processing pipeline.
- Designed and proposed the data provenance framework for ANTARES to answer provenance questions that astronomers would ask.
- Designed the packet format specification for alert data and implemented the simulator for generating alert streams in Python.

University of Arizona USA Tucson, Arizona USA

RESEARCH ASSISTANT WITH DR. RICHARD SNODGRASS ON ANTARES PROJECT

Aug. 2014 - Aug. 2015

- Designed and implemented the database used by ANTARES, as well as the web front-end for querying data produced by ANTARES pipeline using Django and MySQL.
- · Collaborated with astronomers to design, implement and document the Python API for astronomical alert data manipulation.
- Designed and built the autoconfiguration and bootstrap system to run ANTARES in a pseudo-distributed mode using Puppet and Vagrant.

University of Arizona Tucson, Arizona USA

INDEPENDENT STUDY WITH DR. BEICHUAN ZHANG ON NAMED DATA NETWORKING (NDN) PROJECT

Spring 2016 & Fall 2016

- Researched consumer-driven congestion control mechanisms in NDN.
- Implemented TCP-like congestion control algorithms in NDN consumer (in C++), specifically, TCP RENO, CUBIC and VEGAS. Evaluated and studied the performance of each of them in the context of NDN.

University of Arizona USA Tucson, Arizona USA

TEACHING ASSISTANT WITH DR. LESTER MCCANN ON CS460: DATABASE SYSTEMS

Fall 2015 & Spring 2016

- · Held office hours; graded programming and written assignments; prepared solutions for written assignments.
- Designed the final project "Database-driven Web Application" using Oracle, Tomcat and JSP; evaluated students' design and implementation.

University of St. Thomas

St. Paul, Minnesota USA

STUDENT RESEARCHER WITH DR. BRAD RUBIN AND DR. JADIN JACKSON

Aug. 2013 - May. 2014

- We initiated the project "Large-scale Neural Network Modeling with Hadoop" to explore the use of big data technologies in computational neuroscience and I was responsible for investigating graph processing in Hadoop.
- Implemented the neural network with MapReduce model in Hadoop.
- Implemented the neural network with vertex-centric model using Apache Giraph in Hadoop.

Work Experience _____

Danfoss Power Solutions

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

Plymouth, Minnesota USA

June. 2012 - May. 2013

- Migrated the legacy software to the new hardware platform with other team members and conducted unit testing.
- Applied static code analyer FlexeLint to the legacy software written in C.
- Built a tool (in Python) for summarizing, indexing and querying large volume of warning messages produced by FlexeLint.
- Improved overall software quality, identified and corrected several vulnerabilities existed in the legacy code.

July 19, 2017 Shuo Yang · Résumé

EMBEDDED SOFTWARE ENGINEER & TRAINING ASSISTANT

July. 2009 - July. 2011

- Developed Linux device drivers and applications (in C) for various ARM platforms (ARM 9, 11 & Cortex-A8).
- Assisted training instructors in preparing training content and developed technical how-to documents for ARM and Embedded Linux training.
- Instructed trainees in their lab sessions and final design project.

Platomix Technologies. (Start-up company)

Beijing, China

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Feb. 2009 - July. 2009

- Being part of a team that built the initial prototype for Samsung's Remote Test Lab (RTL), I was responsible for the development on RTL device.
- · Implemented the communication protocol (in C++) between RTL device (LiMo platform) and RTL proxy.
- Developed a daemon process (in C++) for RTL device to handles requests from proxy, in order for RTL client to remotely control the device.

Publication

Yang S, Spielman ND, Jackson JC, Rubin BS. Large-scale neural modeling in MapReduce and Giraph. In IEEE International Conference on Electro Information Technology. IEEE Computer Society. 2014. p. 556-561. 6871824. Available from, DOI: 10.1109/EIT.2014.6871824

Selected Coursework

University of Arizona

Database Systems Implementation Implemented Heap File, Buffer Manager and B⁺ Tree components of Minibase in C++.

Principles of Computer Networking Implemented a virtual router in C that runs PWOSPF routing protocol and routes real IP packets.

Principles of Compilation Implemented C- - (a subset of C) compiler (both code generation and optimizations) in C.

Computer Security Implemented a secure chat program using a hybrid protocol (DES + RSA) in Java.

Parallel and Distributed Programming Implemented a MPI critical-path profiler and Redundant MPI protocols in C.

Introduction to Machine Learning Implemented a sparse autoencoder in Python, trained with MNIST handwritten digit dataset.

University of St. Thomas

Big Data Architecture Developed a new design pattern for improving the performance of graph processing in MapReduce.

Data Visualization Explored what are the key factors that make a championship team with NBA dataset using Python, SQLite and R. Built a search engine in Python (web crawler + indexer + query processor) for Shakespeare's whole collection.

Software Engineering Built a genetic programming system in C for automatically solving linear regression problem.

Skills

Programming Languages C/C++, Python, Java, R, JavaScript, SQL

Web Django, HTML, CSS

Database Systems MySQL, SQLite

Parallel and Distributed Programming Pthreads, MPI, MapReduce

Environment/Frameworks/Tools Linux, Hadoop, Giraph, Let, Vagrant